

# SYLVESTER ARIKHAN

#### **Full-Stack Web Developer**

A Full-Stack Web Developer with experience in JavaScript MERN stack and building responsive Web and Mobile Application. My background as a Scientist in Chemistry has provided me the ability to performing quality/assurance, working in a team environment, and putting our customers at the forefront of everything. Very interested in learning about Project Management, new technologies and new languages. keeping up team spirit to achieve organisational goals and keep a lasting legacy.

Email: arikhansylvester@gmail.com Address: Schnellerstrasse 101 Berlin

Phone: 01633731957

Link: https://arikhan.herokuapp.com/

# **Experience**

Feb 2022 - Present

# Software Engineer

#### Gestalt-Robotics GmbH Berlin/Germany

• Development, integration, and testing of users interfaces for software in industrial applications

Jun 2020 - Dec 2021

# Junior Developer (Intern)

# LocaaTech Lagos/Nigeria

- To help real estate customers buy, rent, or solve daily problems with their property
- · Collaborate with senior developers on resolving daily programming task
- Appraise the identified problems on clients' websites and provide solutions using clients' feedback
- Participate and assist in the testing, maintenance, and upgrade of front and backend applications

Apr 2021 - Oct 2021

## Junior Developer (Bootcamp)

#### Career Foundry Berlin

- Completed a 941 hour full stack development training program under the supervision of industry leading mentors and tutors
- The project-based program is divided into 2 parts, Introduction to Front-End Development and Full-Stack Immersion
- Studied and trained through a total of 7 achievements from 60 exercises and 7 projects

#### **Projects**

- Built the server-side component of a (movies web application). The web application
  provide users with access to information about different movies, directors, and
  genres. Users can sign up, update their personal information, and create a list of
  their favorite movies. http://my-flixdbapp.herokuapp.com/documentation.html
- Using Angular to build the client-side for an application called (myFlix), based on its existing server-side code (REST API and database), with supporting documentation. https://ambabasly.github.io/myFlix-Angular-client/welcome

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020

#### **Working Student**

Volkswagen Sachsen GmbH Dresden

• Controlled quality of assembled automatives parts

- Shaped metal sheets making up the frame of the vehicle in a specific time
- Collaborated in a team of German production workers to secure that the production line is complete

Dec 2014 - Jul 2017

# **Assistance Quality Control**

## AKMA Engineering Nigeria Limited Lagos

- Conducted analysis, synthesize, purify, modify and characterize chemical and biochemical content before and during productions
- Developed and conducted programs of analysis to ensure quality control of raw materials, chemical intermediates or final products
- Collected samples, data, and conducted analysis to identify and quantify environmental toxicants through participating in interdisciplinary research
- Developed projects working with chemical engineers, biologists, microbiologist, agronomist, geologists and other professionals

Node.js

ReactNative

Storybook

# **Education**

Oct 2010 - Oct 2014

Bachelor of Sciences in Chemistry

Ambrose Alli University Ekpoma Ekpoma

## Languages

# **English**Native

**German** Intermediate

## **Skills**

Development

JavaSrciptHTML5CSSReact.jsMongoDBSQLTest DrivenAngularDocker

## **Certificates & Courses**

- Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP SAP)
- Project Management Professional (PMP)

# Residence permit

• EU familienangehöriger art 20 rl 2004/38/eg (Gainful Employment Allowed Anywhere Within EU)